Lauren Noeltner

laurennoeltner@gmail.com

(404) 376-7192

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lauren-noeltner-102b731a0

GitHub: https://www.github.com/LNoeltner1/
Portfolio: https://lauren-noeltner.herokuapp.com/

Career Summary

I'm a November 2020 graduate of Georgia Tech's full-time, Full Stack Flex Web Development program. All of my projects can be accessed at the links above. I have completed three years of college at the University of Georgia, majoring in art. I was fortunate to win both local and national awards in painting. Ever since high school, I have worked and have had management positions. Unfortunately, one of those positions was cut short due to the pandemic.

Objective

I am looking for a Full Stack Development position to begin my career in development. I know how to work in groups and independently, and I look forward to sharing experiences and learning with others.

Technical Skills

- Page Design: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Foundation
- Primary Language: JavaScript
- Libraries/frameworks: React, Node, Express, jQuery, Handlebars, Axios, and many other Node packages
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL
- Development Tools: Version control/deployment with GitHub and Heroku, Git, Visual Studio Code, MongoDB Atlas, Robo3T, MySQL Workbench, Postman, Chrome DevTools

Education

- Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, Georgia Institute of Technology, November 2020
- Relevant courses, University of Georgia
 - Color and Composition, 3D Design, Research Statistics, Psychology courses, Physics

Notable Projects

- Cryptic Encounters
 - o Responsibilities: Front and Back End, dialogue mapping/logic, Design, Concept
 - o **Tech used:** JavaScript, Handlebars, Nodejs, Express, MySQL, Foundation
 - Link to Github: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/cryptic-encounters
 - Link to Deployment: https://cryptic-encounter.herokuapp.com/
- GiddyltUp
 - o Responsibilities: Front and Back End, REST/CRUD management, Design, Concept
 - Tech used: JavaScript, MongoDB, Express, React, Nodejs, Bootstrap, Animate.css
 - Link to Github: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/GiddyltUp
 - Link to Deployment: https://giddyitup-eg.herokuapp.com/
- Online/Offline Budget Tracker
 - Responsibilities: Front and Back End (solo project)
 - o **Tech Used:** JavaScript, MongoDB, Nodejs, Express, Morgan
 - Link to GitHub: https://github.com/LNoeltner1/budget-tracker

Link to Deployment: https://budget-tracker-lnoeltner.herokuapp.com/

Work Experience

Senior Team Lead Regal Entertainment Group (Alpharetta, Georgia)—August 2020-Present

- Organizing and delegating tasks to floor staff to effectively run the theater
- Resolving customer complaints or comments satisfactorily to those involved
- Communicated effectively with upper management to coordinate all theater operations

Team Lead Regal Entertainment Group (Atlanta, Georgia)—April 2019-August 2020

Leadership role over cast members, including customer service and accounting.

Cast Member Regal Entertainment Group (Atlanta, Georgia)—February 2017-April 2019

- Interacted with customers positively and became a customer favorite over time
- Spent extra time cleaning to ensure a safe and healthy workspace for all
- Rose to senior cashier quickly, because of money management and accounting

Assistant Manager Victorious Vapors (Athens, Georgia)—June 2016-August 2016

- Managed all sales associates, ensuring that the store was running properly
- Consistently maintained top sales numbers (>\$55,000 over 8 months)
- Authored the employee manual to simplify the on-boarding process and set policies

Sales Associate Victorious Vapors (Athens, Georgia)—August 2015-June 2016

• Developed a strong rapport with clients, creating a wide base of recurring, loyal customers

Dog-Sitter/Walker Freelance pet-care business (Atlanta, Georgia)—May 2012-Present

• Started my own side business of pet-care with great success and many recurring clients

Kennel Technician Briarcliff Animal Clinic (College Park, Georgia)—June 2008-August 2013

- Interviewed new clients and assisted doctors with treatments, diagnoses, and surgeries
- Maintained medical records and other necessary paperwork accurately and diligently
- Nominated by coworkers several times for an "Above and Beyond" award